# STEPHEN CHARLES

print("Hello World!")

I'm a proficient *pythonista* with a background in mathematics, astrophysics and computer science. Particular expertise in managing machine learning pipelines with large data sets involving time series analysis, computer vision and NLP, in addition to interpersonal skills from a range of hospitality roles. Take a look at my Portfolio and Github for examples of recent projects.

## EMPLOYMENT

Feb 2022 - Now

Innovative Technologies - Manchester - Remote

Position

Machine Learning Engineer

Stack

Python, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Git, Bash
• ICU performs accurate age verification to automate associated policy and allow access to age

- restricted purchases and premises, through an ensemble of various ML algorithms.

   Implemented bespoke methods from cutting edge research in SVM's, CNN's, and Bayesian Linear Regression which allow for statistically robust age verification.
- Designed a system by which spoof detection was achievable through the use of belief propagation and anomaly detection.
- Deployed trained models in resource-constrained environments.
- Worked remotely in an agile, communicative, and self-directed manner as part of a collaborative, interdisciplinary, diverse, and geographically-dispersed team.

June - Sept 2020

Facebook (Meta) - London - Remote

Position

Data Scientist, Analytics Intern

STACK

Tableau, SQL, Python, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform
• Performed large-scale data analysis to extract useful business insights.

Dutie

- Identified the ones which were actionable, suggesting recommendations, and influenced the direction of the business by communicating the results to cross-functional groups.
- Classified leads so that the team could work on the most valuable cases, and suggested improvements in the tools and techniques to help scale the team.
- Created dashboards with Tableau on data obtained via SQL queries.

#### EDUCATION

 ${\bf Oct}\ {\bf 2021-2022}$ 

Data Science - University of Bath

MSc

Distinction, Master of Computer Science

Dissertatio

"On The Importance of Knowing What We Don't Know", Neuroscience

The aim was to explore if decodability of an EEG classification signal depends on an individuals capacity for vivid imagination, with a comparison of stochastic and deterministic machine learning.

Module

 $Statistics\ for\ Data\ Science$  - Probability and statistics, with a focus on translating real-world problems into a mathematical framework in data science contexts.

**Machine Learning** - Covered both supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms from Bishop, including how to develop, evaluate and deploy trained models. The second semester involved advanced techniques focused on neural networks with both regression and classification.

Reinforcement Learning - Implemented various agents to solve environments from Sutton & Barto, including Dynamic Programming, Temporal Difference and Deep-Q Learning.

 $Bayesian\ Machine\ Learning\ \text{-}\ Implemented\ approaches}\ such\ as\ bayesian\ inference,\ importance\ sampling,\ monte\ carlo,\ and\ confidence\ interval\ predictions\ both\ from\ scratch\ and\ using\ {\tt bambi}.$ 

 ${\bf Oct}\ {\bf 2020-2021}$ 

Astronomy and Astrophysics - University of Manchester

MSc

Distinction, Master of Physics

Research

Published a program to facilitate the data acquisition and analysis pipeline for TESS automatically, dubbed Firefly (the best Sci-fi show!), which applies nested sampling (Dynesty) to find best fit variables (TransitFit) between the host star and exoplanet.

Sept 2016 - 2020

Mathematics with Computer Science – University of Nottingham

 ${
m MMath}$ 

Upper Second-Class Honours, Master of Mathematics

Research

Dissertation involved working with python to numerically solve spherical cavitation bubble collapse.

Sept 2014 - 2016

Space Engineering – Loughborough College

A-Levels

Mathematics  $A^* \cdot Further Mathematics A \cdot Physics A \cdot Engineering A$ 

A specialised course focused on Engineering with guest lectures at the Space Centre in Leicester.

## GENERAL TECH STACK

## Awards and Qualifications

Languages	Python, C++, SQL, $ ext{LAT}_{ ext{EX}}$	2022	
PACKAGES	Numpy, Pandas, SciPy, AstroPy	2022	AWS DeepRacer Student
ML PACKAGES	Sklearn, Tensorflow, PyTorch	2021	Kaggle Competitions
Data Viz	Tableau, Seaborn	2020	Tableau Desktop Specialist
SCIENTIFIC	Matlab, R, Fortran, Mathematica	2016	Full UK Driving Licence
CLOUD	GCP. AWS	2015	Grade 8 Violin

### **PUBLICATIONS**

2020 - Now SPEARNET - University of Manchester

Actively contributing to exoplanet detection in the spearnet collaboration (Spectroscopy and Photometry of Exoplanetary Atmospheres Network). Spearnet is a UK-Thai collaboration which is using a heterogeneous telescope network to select and follow-up exoplanet transiting systems.

Author

Co-Author Hayes, J J C, E Kerins, J S Morgan et al. (2021) "TransitFit: an exoplanet transit fitting package

for multi-telescope datasets and its application to WASP-127 b, WASP-91 b, and WASP-126  $^{1.14}$ 

b", 1–14.

## ACADEMIC WORK EXPERIENCE

Autumn 2018 Scholarship – National University of Singapore

Scholarship Obtained a scholarship to study a crash course in Korean language for 5 weeks and to learn about

the culture and history of the changing landscapes of Singapore. Upon completion, applied to spend

the Autumn semester here successfully.

Sept 2017 - 2019 Physics Outreach - The University of Nottingham

Outreach I began, on a voluntary basis, promoting physics via social media which eventually evolved into a

paid role in which I mediated with events staff in the department to ensure successful participation.

Part of the role was ensuring inclusivity, and how best to target minority groups.

Summer 2018 Magical Maths – St Mary's Catholic Primary School, Nottingham

Outreach Organisation of weekly sessions to promote mathematics to primary school children, in line with

the national curriculum.

Summer 2014 Research Intern - Space Research Centre, The University of Leicester

Intern During my first college year I gained work experience at the University of Leicester Space Research

Centre, assisting in the development of an astrobiology rock-sampling tool called SPLIT for use on

Mars.

#### INTERESTS

PHOTOGRAPHY Avid adventurer and keen Music Self taught Guitar, Piano, Violin.

astronomer. This hobby pushes the ART Into optical illusions like the works of

boundaries of my interest in both. Escher, Bridget Riley etc.

Exploring the peaks, lakes and **Literature** Love the classics, Jules Verne, H.P.

anywhere with hills. Love to spend Lovecraft, H.G. Wells etc.

weeks away camping.

General Into Sci fi and anything spacey!

## REFERENCES

Hiking

NAMEDr. Eamonn KerinsProf. CJ HarrisDr. John HoltTITLESenior LecturerResearch ProfessorResearch EngineerEMAILeamonn.kerins@manchester.ac.ukchrisharris57@msn.comjmch1@le.ac.uk

University of Manchester University of Southampton University of Leicester Department of Physics Department of Engineering Department of Physics

PhD, DSc, FREng, Fellow PhD, FREng